# 掉到田头的话你又去摸它呀
It drops to the field you’ll have to find it
# 摸它
Find it
# 马上拿（鱼）罩罩去罩
Immediately cover it with a cover
# 今天我们这边天气突然之间不知道为什么有点冷
Somehow today the weather becomes cold all of a sudden
# 所以今天我做一个鱼来吃
So I’m making a fish today
# 四伯爷 想吃啥子鱼
Uncle, which type of fish would you like
# 你反正做最安逸最好吃的那种做法嘛
Whichever one you think that’s nice and delicious
# 那我就做一个花椒鱼喽
Then I’ll make a “Sichuan peppercorn fish”
# 要的呀
No problems
# 好嘛
Alright
# 这一次我们从它的边上下刀
This time we cut it from the side
# 不从中间下
Not from the side
# 草鱼的话从中间更好下（刀）一点
For freshwater fish it’s better to cut in the middle
# 这个鱼的话就从边上下（刀）
For this one we’ll cut from the side
# 有刺看划到手不得了哦
The bones will poke you and it will hurt
# 不得 我杀了这么多年的鱼害怕会划到手
Don’t worry, I’ve been doing this for years
# 还是要小心点
Still be careful
# 抠腮是你的拿手戏
Gutting fish is your specialty
# 这个鱼的腮你看好大一把
Look how big are the fish gills
# 好
Alright
# 我就把它砍大坨点哦
I’ll chop them into bigger chunks
# 要的
Fine with me
# 尾巴都还在动
Its tail is still moving
# 尾巴就是刺多得很
The tail has too many bone
# 这是活动肉
This is an active muscle
# 再改下刀
Cut it into smaller chunks
# （砍)下去
(Chop) it down
# 开它的后背
Open up it’s back
# 改一刀
Cut once
# 这样再改一刀
And then cut it another time like this
# 就可以了
That will do
# 现在我们这个鱼就洗干净了
Now we’ve cleaned up the fish
# 把它腌一下
Let’s marinate it for a while
# 放点盐腌一下
We’ll marinate it with some salt
# 然后再放一点点料酒
And some cooking wine
# 稍微和一下就可以了
And lightly mix it up a bit
# 给它收一下
Let it sit for a while
# 然后我们准备一小块仔姜
Let’s prepare a small chunk of young ginger
# 我们这个仔姜跟这个二荆条辣椒
This young ginger and the Erjintiao chilli,
# 是最后快要起锅的时候才放
Is to be added in lastly
# 这个放进去煮久了反而味道不好
This won’t taste good if it’s cooked for too long
# 然后再切点泡椒
Then cut some pickled chilli
# 这个是必须要用的
This is a necessity
# 这个多辣哦
This is pretty hot
# 神得起不（受得了不）四伯爷你
Han you handle it? Uncle
# 没得事的
I’m fine
# 好嘛
Your said it
# 泡椒
Pickled chilli
# 你那都浪多泡椒这又整点小米辣
You have already got so many pickled chilli and you are still adding Xiaomila chilli
# 好 现在来看一下我们这个
Now let’s look at this
# 也是很重要的一个调料
This is a very important seasoning
# 就是大蒜和姜
That is garlic and ginger
# 这个大蒜我们切这么多
We have so much garlic
# 主要是用来炸这个蒜油
Mainly it’s for the garlic oil
# 待会儿首先下锅的就是这个蒜
Later we’ll cook garlic first
# 然后我们这个姜切成片
Then we cut ginger into slices
# 这老姜可以就先下锅去煮
The old ginger can be cooked first
# 我们切这么多料
We’ve prepared so many ingredients
# 其实煮这个鱼还有最重要的一点就是
There is another important point in cooking this fish
# 鱼一定要是活的是鲜的
The fish has to be fresh and alive
# 就是说我们四川这边的家庭吧
That’s true for families in Sichuan
# 吃这个鱼放这么多调料进去
We’ve used so many ingredients
# 去烧一条死鱼对不起这个调料
It’s not worth using the ingredients on a dead fish
# 是不是这样说四伯爷
Is that right Uncle?
# 是安
You are right
# 可惜了那些材料
Waste of ingredients
# 挽一个小葱就行了
Make a nod with scallion
# 小葱待会儿煮汤的时候丢到里面煮
We put it into the soup later
# 加坨豆腐进去
Add a chunk of tofu
# 跟那个鱼一起煮
Together with the fish
# 这个豆腐煮起 肯定很好吃噻
This tofu must taste amazing cooked like this
# 香这个豆腐就是
Just very aromatic
# 你煮鱼要煮多久这个豆腐煮久点就（更好吃）
Tofu taste better with the time you cook it
# 要的 四伯爷帮我拿哈
Alright, uncle take it for me
# 要的呀
For sure
# 首先把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 加入宽油
Add Kuan You
# 将油温烧至7成热之后下入腌制好的鱼
Bring the oil temperature to 210 degree and drop in marinated fish.
# 炸至1分钟将鱼捞出备用
Fry for a minute then drain out set aside
# 倒出多余的植物油后锅中留少许底油
Pour out excess oil then left a small amount of base oil
# 加入姜蒜爆香
Add ginger and garlic then bring out the aroma
# 你不放花椒啊
Don’t you add peppercorn?
# 花椒最后来
We add that at last
# 最后给它炸哈油
Lastly, we fry it with oil
# 加入泡椒和干辣椒
Add pickled chilli and dried chilli
# 加入豆瓣酱炒出红油
Add doubanjiang then stir-fry out the red oil
# 加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Add a moderate amount of water then bring it to a boil
# 水开之后再放鱼下去呀
Then we add fish when the water boils
# 水烧开之后开始调味
Then we start seasoning
# 锅中加入食用盐
Add salt in the wok
# 鸡精
Chicken concentrate powder
# 白糖
Sugar
# 生抽
Light soy sauce
# 香醋
Vinegar
# 调好味之后加入炸好的鱼块和豆腐
Then we add in fried fish and tofu
# 好 可以了
Alright that’s it
# 下去给它煮
Boil it
# 开大火烧5分钟烧至入味
Turn the heat on high then boil for 5 min until it’s seasoned well
# 姜丝最后放
Add sliced ginger at last
# 还要放花椒
Then we add Sichuan peppercorn
# 放早了煮来仔姜是苦的
The ginger will taste bitter if it’s cooked for too long
# 中途加入葱结
Add scallion nod in the middle
# 5分钟之后加入青红椒和仔姜丝
Add sliced chilli and sliced ginger 5 min later
# 1分钟之后即可出锅装盆
We can serve it after 1 min
# 然后再次把锅洗干净加入适量菜籽油
Then we clean up the wok and add some vegetable oil
# 油温6成热加入一把青花椒泼在鱼上面即可
When the oil is raised to 180 degree and pour it on the fish with Sichuan pepper
# 来 伯娘添（盛）饭
Come untie fill the rice
# 好
Alright
# 我给你添（盛）
Let me help you with (the rice)
# 你先尝哈味道嘛四伯爷
Taste it first uncle
# 我先尝哈这个豆腐看
Let’s try the tofu first
# 你添（盛）饭吗
Do you want some rice?
# 伯娘尝哈鱼
Try some fish untie
# 好嘛好
Alright
# 鱼才嫩
The fish is so tender
# 看
Look
# 好大块哦
It’s so big
# 夹就是
Just help yourself
# 就是要大坨才好吃
Bigger chunk taste better
# 这个鱼非常嫩
This fish is very tender
# 就是因为上了粉之后走了一下油锅
Lightly powdered then fried in oil
# 而且还一点腥味都没有
And you don’t taste any fishy smell
# 味道才鲜
Packed with umami taste
# 是嘛
Sure
# 嗯
Yeah
# 这个鱼泡我喜欢吃
I like this fish bubble
# 你吃噻
You have it
# 可以安
Really good
# 我夹了哦
I’m having it
# 夹嘛
Go ahead
# 你吃嘛
You go ahead
# 嗯
Alright
# 可以噶
Very good
# 这个鱼跟豆腐样好嫩哦
This fish and tofu is very tender
# 其实我这个鱼是吃鱼头
Actually I like the fish head
# 这个样的啊
Is that so?
# 这个大头鱼的话其实就是吃鱼头
It’s head is the best in this big head fish
# 鱼头最好吃
Fish head tastes the best
# 一点腥味都没得
Not even a hint of fishy smell
# 这个不见的辣（不辣）
This is not very hot
# 合适得很
Very well balanced
# 其实我们水煮鱼也可以这么做
Actually we can cook shui zhu yu with this method
# 就是最后那一下用那个菜油把它烧熟了
Lastly we bring the vegetable oil to temperature
# 抓一把花椒炸一下再倒到这个上面
Grab a handful of Sichuan peppercorn on top of this
# 刺多得很注意到
Be careful with the fish bones
# 其实辣的话不是很辣
It’s not very hot to be fair
# 不辣
Not a all
# 主要是这个花椒香味特别香
Mainly because the Sichuan peppercorn is very aromatic
# 这个豆腐跟那个鱼的味道
The taste of the tofu and the fish
# 安逸
AMAZING!
# 好了大家如果你们那边天气比较冷的话
Alright guys if the weather in your place is cold
# 可以尝试一下这个鱼
You can try this fish
# 安逸
Very nice!
# 真的很嫩
Very tender!
# 这样子跟它吃火锅样噶
It’s almost like hotpot
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright that’s the end of this video
# 我们要吃饭了
We are going to eat
# ```